《生活大爆炸》前情提要
Previously, on The Big Bang Theory...
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
看来你们就是我的新邻居了  我叫佩妮
Guess I'm your new neighbor. Penny.
-我叫莱纳德  他叫谢尔顿  -你们好
- Oh. Leonard. Sheldon. - Hi.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - ‭Hi.
- Hi. ‭- Hi.
那是我的专座
That's where I sit.
霍华德·沃罗威茨
Howard Wolowitz.
加州理工应用物理学部门
Caltech Department of Applied Physics.
佩妮
Penny?
莱纳德
Leonard.
拉杰
Raj?
他会说英语  他只是无法跟女人对话
He speaks English-- he just can't speak to women.
我们的孩子一定会又聪明又好看
Our babies will be smart and beautiful.
终于走运一回啦
Finally caught a break.
♪ 软猫猫 ♪
♪ Soft kitty... ♪
你们认识我女朋友吧  伯纳黛特
You know my girlfriend, Bernadette.
霍华德  我饿了
Howard, I'm hungry!
♪ 暖猫猫 ♪
♪ Warm kitty... ♪
♪ 小毛球猫猫 ♪
♪ Little ball of fur... ♪
我是艾米·菲拉·福勒  你是谢尔顿·库珀
I'm Amy Farrah Fowler. You're Sheldon Cooper.
逗你玩
Bazinga.
欢迎收看由谢尔顿·库珀出品的
Welcome to the premiere episode
《有趣的旗帜》之首播集
of Sheldon Cooper Presents Fun with Flags.
我要上太空了  严格来说
I'm going up in space. Technically,
我是宇航员了
I'm an astronaut.
亲娘咧
Oy vey!
你在和我说话
You're talking to me.
是的
I am. ‭
伯纳黛特·玛丽安·罗斯滕科斯基
Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski...
我们现在宣布你们成为夫妻
We now pronounce you husband and wife.
艾米
Amy?
Howard?
愤怒的艾米
Angry Amy?
我不希望你
I don't want you to say it
仅仅因为社交规矩而说出来
just because social convention dictates that you...
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes. ‭
我们结婚啦
We did it!
我比预想中更享受
Well, I enjoyed that more than I thought I would.
不知道哪个才是哈雷
I wonder which one's Halley.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
那...
That...
是怀了的意思吗
means... positive?
超不对称性  就是这个了
Super asymmetry, that's it!
我们的论文是对的
Our paper was right.
-我们做到了  -我们做到了吗
- We did it! - ‭We did it?
我们做到了
We did it!
♪ 6乘10的8次方个镭原子在铅罐里 ♪
♪ Six times ten to the eighth atoms of a radium in a lead jar ♪
♪ 6乘10的8次方个镭 ♪
♪ Six times ten to the eighth atoms of radium ♪
♪ 如果镭的半衰期过了 ♪
♪ If the half-life of radium should happen to pass ♪
♪ 3乘10的8次方个镭原子在铅罐里 ♪
♪ Three times ten to the eighth atoms of a radium in a lead jar...  ♪
希望你快唱到0了
Really hope you're almost to zero.
没  半衰期的美妙之处就在这里
No, see, that's the beauty of half-lives:
当减少到接近0的时候  就基本无法被探测到
it's impossible to determine when you'll arrive at zero.
就像儿歌"一只青蛙一张嘴"
It's like "Wheels on the Bus"
但那青蛙拥有的器官是未知数
if the bus had an unknowable number of parts.
我们需要再喝点咖啡
Yeah, we're gonna need more coffee.
我跟你去  莱纳德  你要吗
Yep. I'm with you. Leonard, coffee?
又黑劲儿又大那种  像卢克·凯奇一样
Black and strong, like Luke Cage.
漫威旗下的超级英雄人物  是一名强壮的黑人
我太累  没力气被你给恶心了
I'm too tired to even be disturbed by that.
-谢尔顿你呢  -绝对不喝
- Sheldon? - Mm, absolutely not, no.
诺贝尔奖委员会随时有可能打来
The Nobel committee will be making the calls to inform
宣布赢家  我现在唯一需要的药物
the winners at any minute, so the only drug I need
就是由于期待胜利
is the endorphins pumping through my brain
所以不断注往我脑中的内啡肽
in anticipation of our victory.
严格来说  比起内啡肽
Well, technically, anticipation wouldn't be mediated
多巴胺更能有效缓解渴望  不过呢
by endorphins as much as dopamine, but, you know,
你也熬一整晚了  这题我就不多跟你计较了
you've been up all night, so I'll give you that one.
不是吧  他闭上嘴的那秒就睡着吗
Really? The second he stops talking?
我们应该叫醒他吗
Well... should we wake him up?
他的确有说过
Well, he did say if he fell asleep,
如果他睡着  我们有权扇醒他
we were allowed to slap him awake.
太兴奋啦
Oh, boy.
等等  凭什么是你来扇
Wait a minute. Why do you get to do it?
因为我先喊先赢
'Cause I called it.
喊了算个屁啊  这权利是看资格的
Well, you can't just call it. You have to earn it.
所以你有这个资格吗
Oh, and you've earned it?
全天下没人比我更有资格
No one has earned it more than me.
你还有一生可以扇他
You have your whole life to smack him around.
这是我的机会
This is my time.
行  那你别扇歪
Fine. Don't miss.
这又不是打排球  我能行
It's not a volleyball. I can handle it.
等等  别急
Oh, wait. Hang on.
等你老了  你会希望有记录留念
When you're old, you are gonna want a record of this.
太赞啦
Oh, oh, yeah.
用慢动作拍摄  我想看到他脸颊被打的涟漪
Do it in slo-mo. I want to see his cheeks ripple.
准备  上
Ready... go.
要揭晓啦
It's happening!
未知来电者  肯定是他们了
Unknown caller. It's got to be them.
好  开公放
Okay, put it on speaker.
-你好  -你好啊
- Hello? - ‭Hi.
俚们嚎  这是来自瑞典的电花
Hello. This is Sweden calling.
请问四库珀博士与胡乐博士吗
Is this Dr. Cooper and Dr. Fowler?
-是的  -是
- Yes. - ‭Yeah.
恭西啦
Congratulations.
偶很高新通知你们  你们淫了诺贝鹅...
It is my pleasure to inform you that you've won the Nobel Prize
诺贝鹅傻逼奖
in being suckers...!
他的瑞典口音太真实了
His Swedish accent was very convincing.
时候到了
This is it!
你打来干嘛  霍华德
What do you want, Howard?
我们打来问问你们收到通知了没
We were just calling to see if you'd heard yet.
还没呢
We haven't.
但谢谢你们起个大早打来关心啊
But thank you for getting up so early to call.
你们真是太有心了
That was very thoughtful.
拜托  我们有两个孩子
Oh, please. We have two little kids.
我们都醒一个小时了
We've been up for an hour.
你们有谁扇到谢尔顿了吗
Did anyone get to slap Sheldon?
没
No.
好吧  你们接到电话后再打给我们吧
Okay, well, call us when you hear.
那现在干嘛
All right, now what?
要不我们玩个游戏来消磨时间
Oh, why don't we play a game to pass the time?
现在  我脑海里有个数字
Here. Uh, I am thinking of a number.
提示  是一个素数的立方的立方
Hint: it's a cube of a cube of a prime.
那有无数的可能性
There's an infinite number of possibilities.
怎么  你难道还有别的事干吗
What, you got somewhere to be?
是我的电话
Oh. That's me.
你好
Hello?
对  我是福勒博士
Yes, this is Dr. Fowler.
我知道了
I see.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
我们赢了
We won.
恭喜你们
Congratulations!
天啊
Oh, my God!
-我们成功了  -我知道
- We did it. - I know.
你能相信这是真的吗
Can you believe it? ?
问得好  万一是我在做梦呢
That's a good point. What if I'm dreaming?
我们赢得诺贝尔奖啦
We won the Nobel Prize!
翻译     最变态的霍华赛 爱YY的妮妮猫火辣的猫中佩妮 油腻的印度拉希
校对     一切始于YY猫 一切终于赛太公
后期      灰灰是菇凉      时间轴    加森
总监     YY猫
生
活
大
爆
炸
第十二季  第二十三集
当一位诺贝尔奖得主的伴侣是什么感觉
And how does it feel to be married to a Nobel Prize winner?
-那你说呢  -以艾米当核心人物
- You tell me. - Oh. Amy-centric--
这个角度看还挺有意思
what a fun way to look at it.
-我也觉得  -你当然会啊  这不无道理
- I think so. - You would. That makes sense.
我姥姥给我发来祝贺短信
Aw. It's a congratulations text from my meemaw.
我妈也给我发了一条
Ooh. Oh, and there's one from my mom.
还有我姐姐
And my sister.
我哥哥
Oh, and my brother.
我哥哥的前妻
And my brother's ex-wife.
我哥哥的另一个前妻
My brother's other ex-wife.
天啊  怎么没人告诉我得了诺贝尔奖后
Boy, they don't tell you when you win a Nobel
手机耗电量会激增
it chews up your phone battery.
我也收到了
Oh, that's me.
是药房通知我的药可以取了
It's CVS. My prescription's ready.
还有我爸的短信
Oh, and also my dad.
他说恭喜我  还说他爱我
He says congratulations and he loves me.
没提到我吗
Nothing about me?
你爸也给我发了  没事了
Oh, it's your dad. I'm good.
仔细想想
You know, when you think about it,
现在我们是诺贝尔奖的得主了
now that we're Nobel Prize winners,
-我们的名字将永远被连结在一起  -我们是夫妻
- our names will be linked together forever. - ?We're married.
我们的名字早就被连结在一起了
Our names are already linked together forever.
拜托  那只是一张纸而已
Oh, please. That's just a piece of paper.
这可是一张纸和一枚奖牌啊
This is a piece of paper and a medal.
感觉好奇怪
It's weird.
虽然我没觉得有什么不一样
I don't really feel different,
但我猜我们的生活将从此改变
but I guess our lives will never be the same.
还好吧  我们现在就像平时一样去上班
Oh, I don't know. We're going to work like always.
我穿裤子时还是双腿同时穿
I still put my pants on both legs at a time.
总有一天你会自食苦果
One day that's gonna end very badly.
恭喜两位  获奖的感觉怎么样
Congratulations. How does it feel?
我们很乐意回答你们的问题
Okay, w-we're happy to answer your questions,
请一个个来  好吗
Just, um, one at a time, please?
库珀博士
Dr. Cooper!
库珀博士还会回来吗
Is Dr. Cooper coming back?
不会  下一个问题
No. Next question.
你是用左手打还是右手打
Was it your left hand or your right hand?
右手
Right.
打得他口水都飞出来了
Spit actually flew out of his mouth.
小伙子们
Hey, fellas.
能帮我个忙吗
Can you do me a favor?
有选择的余地吗
Do we have a choice?
真会说笑  没有
Ha-ha! No.
谢尔顿和艾米现在正式成为超级明星
Sheldon and Amy are now officially superstars,
新闻媒体肯定会去采访他们的家人和朋友们
and the press will be reaching out to their family and friends for comment.
所以我们的口径必须一致
So that we're all on the same page,
形容他俩时  统一用词应该是"怪杰"
the word we're gonna use to describe them is "quirky."
重点不在怪  在杰
And not quirky. More like quirky.
所以不是怪里怪气夫妻档吗
So not Mr. And Mrs. Wackadoodle?
真会说笑
Ho-ho-ho!
你这个尖酸嫉妒的小人
You bitter, envious little man.
感谢大家的掌声
Thank you so much.
我们应该称他们为什么
And what do we call that?
怪杰
Quirky.
库珀博士  我能占用你一分钟时间吗
Dr. Cooper, can I get a minute of your time?
有人吗
Hello?
-需要帮忙吗  -还真是需要
- Can I help you? - Uh, yeah, actually.
我约了跟库珀博士做得奖专访
Um, I had an appointment to interview Dr. Cooper about the Nobel.
稍等
Hang on a second.
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
抱歉  他不在
Sorry, he's not here.
真倒霉  我都要截稿了
Damn. I've got a deadline.
不知道这样能不能帮上你
I don't know if it helps you at all,
但我是他全世界最好的朋友
but I'm his best friend in the whole world.
-真的吗  -我还是一名宇航员
- Really? - And an astronaut.
来吧  请我喝杯咖啡  你就有素材可以写了
Come on, you can buy me a cup of coffee, and I'll tell you about both.
里面的人没事吧
Everyone okay in there?
走开
Go away!
艾米
Amy?
拉杰  拜托  别来烦我
Raj, please, not now.
你怎么啦
Hey, what's wrong?
网上都是我的照片
My picture's all over the Internet,
而我看起来好丑
and I look terrible.
不会啊  我看看
No. Let me see.
这可真是死亡角度  不丑才怪
Well, that is an unfortunate angle.
但谁在乎啊
But who cares?
你刚获得诺贝尔奖
You just won the Nobel.
你该为这一刻感到骄傲
You should be proud of this moment.
我知道我不该在乎我的外表
I know I shouldn't care about how I look,
我也从未觉得我会在乎
and I never thought I did.
这样愚蠢又肤浅   可我就是忍不住
It-It's stupid and shallow, but I just can't help it.
我真的这么老土吗
Am I really this frumpy?
不  你是一个美女
No. No, you are a beautiful woman.
如果你实在因为这些照片而不开心
By the way, if you're not happy with those pictures,
那就做点小改变
then make some changes.
剪个头发  买新衣服
Get a haircut, new clothes,
新眼镜  更大的眼镜
new glasses, big glasses...
不戴眼镜最好  这样你就看不见这些照片了
No glasses-- then you won't be able to see those pictures.
听起来好花钱啊
Sounds expensive.
等等  如果我没记错的话
Excuse me, I-if I'm not mistaken,
诺贝尔奖的奖金相当可观
the Nobel comes with a substantial cash prize.
你们打算怎么花
What were you gonna spend it on?
我们还没认真想过这件事
Hadn't really thought about it.
谢尔顿倒是看上了几件多克斯的衣服[休闲品牌]
Sheldon's got his eyes on some new Dockers.
拜托  你也在自己身上花点钱吧
Come on. Do something for yourself.
或许我可以换个发型
Well, I suppose I could get a haircut.
再买点化妆品  买点新衣服
And some makeup and a new wardrobe
如果你的陪购小伙伴有喜欢的东西
and a little thank you gift for your shopping buddy
再顺便给他买个小谢礼  走吧
if we see something he likes. Come on.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
比弗利山庄  他中意的都在那儿
Beverly Hills, where the things he likes are.
晚饭做好了吗
Dinner ready?
你不做就没得吃
Not unless you cooked.
为什么这篇介绍谢尔顿的文章写的内容都是你
Why is this article about Sheldon all about you?
让我看看
Let me see.
很好  他们选了我在太空总署的照片
Oh, good, they used my NASA picture.
上面怎么说你是他最好的朋友
Why does it say that you're his best friend?
莱纳德才是他最好的朋友
Leonard's his best friend.
不  莱纳德的角色更类似于
No. Leonard has always been
一个猴子管家
kind of a monkey butler.
每当谢尔顿陷入困境时
Whenever Sheldon got into a scrape,
他想找的帮手只有我
I was his go-to guy.
谢尔顿什么时候陷入过困境呀
When did he get into a scrape?
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
还记得他把手卡在橄榄罐头瓶里
W-- Remember when he had a panic attack
搞得惊恐发作那一次吗
'cause his hand got stuck in a jar of olives?
是我说服他松开那些橄榄
I was the one who told him to let go of the olives.
拜托  这也不代表你是他最好的朋友吧
Please, that doesn't make you his best friend.
你知道记者还问我...
You know, that reporter asked me
能不能帮他联系上...
if I could put him in touch with...
艾米最好的朋友
Amy's best friend.
那就是佩妮
That's Penny.
那可不一定哦
Doesn't have to be.
什么茶适合现在的我呢
What kind of tea is appropriate
自从获得了诺贝尔奖后  身边一切开始改变
for winning a Nobel Prize and now everything is changing
我有一种跟现实脱节的感觉
and you feel unmoored from reality?
我不知道  伯爵茶吗
I don't know. Earl Grey?
这个奖我渴望了一辈子了
You know, this is something I've wanted my whole life.
但我大概从来没考虑过
But I guess I never considered
得奖后我的人生会因此而不同
how everything would be different.
兄弟  我知道这些变化让你措手不及
Buddy, I-I know it all feels overwhelming right now,
但我向你保证  一切都会恢复原样
but I promise you, things will settle down.
里面根本没有伯爵茶  你这个臭骗子
There's no Earl Grey! You filthy liar!
佩妮在吗
Hey, is Penny here?
不在  怎么了
No. Why?
我想让她欣赏一下我最新的作品
I wanted to show her my latest creation.
请让我向各位介绍...
I give you...
艾米·菲拉·福勒博士
Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler.
艾米  你实在太美了
Wow. Amy, you look amazing.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢尔顿  你觉得怎么样
Sheldon, what do you think?
我更喜欢你之前的模样
I like you better the way you were.
可她现在多漂亮啊
But she looks beautiful!
经典优雅的线条
Classic lines,
发色和肤色相得映彰
colors that complement her skin tone,
一分钟完成从办公室到派对狂欢的无缝对接
and hair that goes from "office" to "on the town" in minutes.
我不在乎  改回原来的样子
I don't care. Put it back.
我挺喜欢我这造型
I like the way I look.
可是我不喜欢
Well, I don't!
我的错  我家的伯爵茶喝完了
My fault. I was out of Earl Grey.
谢尔顿  你这样真的很不礼貌
Sheldon, that was really rude.
抱歉  艾米本应是我坚定不变的磐石
I'm sorry. Amy is the one constant I can count on,
可她也开始变了
and now she's changing.
她只是换了发型和衣服
It's just a haircut and some clothes.
不  这是最后一根稻草
No, it's the last straw!
我受不了了
I can't take any more!
不敢相信吧  他们终于修好这破电梯了
Can you believe it? They finally fixed the elevator.
真是一场恶梦
This is a nightmare.
他怎么了
What's with him?
他刚赢得了诺贝尔奖  老婆又美丽动人
He won a Nobel Prize, and his wife looks amazing.
懂了
Yeah, got it.
你怎么下来的
How did you get down here?
坐电梯呀  速度超快的
The elevator. It's really fast.
我想自己独处一会
I-I need to be alone right now.
不要跟着我
Don't try to follow me.
好吧  要我载你一程吗
All right. You need a ride?
那敢情好  谢谢
That'd be great. Thank you.
我早该料到会这样
I should've seen this coming.
别这么说  你有权利换个发型
Oh, stop. You're allowed to get a haircut.
我知道
I know.
但我应该循序渐进地做
But I should've done it gradually.
比如...
You know, like...
十年内通过300次理发变成这样
maybe 300 tiny haircuts over a ten-year period.
好了  你应该看到事情积极的一面
Okay, you need to focus on the positive.
你赢得了诺贝尔奖
You won a Nobel Prize.
我扇了谢尔顿一耳光
I slapped Sheldon.
今天可真是实现诸多梦想的好日子呀
A lot of dreams came true today.
对  你说得对
You know, you're right.
今天是我的大日子
This is a huge day for me,
我有资格好好享受这一切
and I'm allowed to enjoy it
而不用担心这会对我丈夫产生什么影响
without worrying how it's going to affect my husband.
是我错觉  还是杀气突然浓厚了起来啊
Is it me or did it just get fierce in here?
变化实在太多太快了
All this change is just too much.
先是有记者围攻
The reporters,
到上班开始备受关注
the attention at work,
现在连艾米都开始变了
and now even Amy's changed.
喝慢一点
Slow down.
我正在玩一个饮酒游戏
‭I'm playing a drinking game.
每次你提到"变"这个字
Every time you say the word "Change,"
我就喝一大口
I take a slug.
这样你还能开车送我回家吗
Are you gonna be able to drive me home?
除非你改变话题
Mm. Not unless you change the subject.
我也提到这个字了
Now I said it.
你大概是唯一一个获得了
You know, you're the only person who could win
科学界最高奖励却还愁眉苦脸的人
the biggest prize in science and still be upset about it.
我只是...
It's just...
每当我想到获奖这事
all the times I thought about winning,
我都没想过它会改...
I never thought about how it would ch--
影响我的生活
affect my life.
不好意思  我真的很担心你的肝
I'm sorry, I'm genuinely concerned about your liver.
行
Okay.
好吧  我不逗你了
Fine, I'll stop playing.
你不停说你希望一切都保持不变
You know, you go on and on about wanting things to stay the same,
但我认识你之后  你改变了很多
but you've changed a lot since I met you.
你喝醉之后嘴可真毒
Oh, you are a mean drunk.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
你现在有很多朋友
You have a ton of friends,
你结婚了  搬进了新公寓
you got married, moved into a new apartment,
你还戴过一次棒球帽
you wore a baseball hat that one time.
你做爱的次"数"都快赶上我手指的"数"量了
Heck, you've had sex almost as many times as I have fingers.
-比那还多  -什...
- More. - W...
多这么多次
By this many.
你个小淫娃
You dog!
《复仇者联盟》的预告片让我欲火焚身
It was the Avengers trailer.
懂了
Oh. Mm-hmm.
我也成长了  我以前在这里当过酒保呢
You know, I've grown, too. I used to be the bartender back there.
此话不假
‭That's true.
现在换成了另一个完全不同的女人
And now there is a completely different woman
她刚调砸了我要的饮料
who botched my drink order.
65%可乐  35%健怡可乐是有多难制作啊
How hard is 65% Coke, 35% Diet Coke?
从她杀气腾腾的表情判断
Well, judging by the look on her face,
里面至少有1%是口水
it's at least one percent saliva.
不过我懂你意思啦
I do take your point.
你也结婚了
You know, you're also married,
有成功的事业
you have a successful career,
你不会再穿得像要去勾引码头边的水手
you no longer dress like you're trying to attract sailors by the wharf.
所以这世界唯一不变的事
So, I guess the only thing that actually stays the same
就是这世界一直在变
is that things are always changing.
这观点很有意思
Interesting.
你是说改变的必然性
So you're saying the inevitability of change
可能是普适常量
might be a universal constant.
应该是比这个意义更深远  不过是啦
Well, there's a little more to it than that, but, yeah, sure.
看啊  伯纳黛特上电视了
Oh. Hey, look, that's Bernadette.
诺贝尔奖得主夫妇最好的两位朋友
霍华德和伯纳黛特·沃罗威茨
我都记不清有多少次福勒博士想放弃时
I can't tell you how many times Dr. Fowler was gonna give up
我都会跟她说
and I would say to her,
"艾米  作为你最好的朋友
"Amy, as your best friend,
我是不会让你放弃的"
I'm not gonna let you quit."
老娘又要开喝了
Okay, I'm drinking again.
我跟你一起喝  服务生
I'll join you. Waitress,
95%夏威夷宾治  5%伏特加
uh, 95% Hawaiian Punch, five percent vodka.
我告诉你们  有一次
Let me tell you about the time
诺贝尔奖得主先生想吃橄榄...
Mr. Nobel Laureate wanted olives...
这个故事可逗趣了
This is a good one.
伏特加还是增加到10%吧
You know what, 90/10!
我喜欢我的新发型
You know, I like the way my hair looks.
我受够了整天伴君如伴虎一般
I'm done tiptoeing around him.
惯坏他我们人人有份
We're all guilty of it.
但为什么呢
But why?
因为我们怕惹他不高兴
'Cause we were afraid to upset him.
但不管怎样他还是会生气的
Which happens anyway.
这一切到此为止
Well, that's over.
我不要再惯着他了  像什么
I'm-I'm done enabling him. Like,
这里是他的专座
this is his spot
恒温器必须调到他舒服的那一档
and-and the thermostat has to be set to his comfort level,
即使他已经不住在这了
even though he doesn't even live here anymore
我却每天冷个半死
and I'm always chilly.
所以你才总是穿着连帽卫衣吗
Is that why you wear a hoodie all the time?
为什么...  没错
Why would-- Yes!
都是为了迁就谢尔顿
To accommodate Sheldon!
还有那玩意
And what-what about this-this thing?
为什么会放在这里  我来告诉你们
Why is it here? I'll tell you why.
因为我搬进来时这东西就在这
Because it was here when I moved in,
而且毫无原因  他却不准我碰它
and, for no earthly reason, he forbade me to touch it.
如果你不喜欢
Well, if you don't like it,
就挪走啊
get rid of it.
放进杂物房
Put it in the closet.
我这就搬
You know what, I will.
这就是不准你碰的原因吧
I bet that's the reason.
等一下
Hang on.
怎么样
What do you think?
你想试试吗
Want to give it a try?
其实
Well, you know,
当年我搬进这栋大楼时  电梯是好的
the elevator did work when I moved into the building.
所以走楼梯才是改变
So going up and down the stairs was a change,
这代表坐电梯其实是恢复原状
which means this would actually be a return to the status quo.
-但反过来说  我觉得...  -进去
- But, conversely, I think... - ‭Get in!
好刺激好狂野
This is wild.
未完待续
碳
Carbon.
两个月后
氢
Hydrogen.
碳
Carbon.
最后一个
And last but not least,
碳
carbon.
我可能是胶水吸多了说疯话
This might be the glue talking,
但过去这139个半小时我过得很愉快
but that was a very pleasurable 139 and a half hours.
我同意
Agreed.
这到底是什么DNA
What kind of DNA is this, anyway?
我当时想设计
I was trying to design the genetic code
高级人种的基因序列
of an advanced race of human being.
-这其实是我仅有的几次失败之一  -出什么问题了
- One of my rare failures, actually. - What went wrong?
小球不断粘到我裤子上
The balls kept sticking to my pants.
放着等它干吧
Let's just let it dry.
-嗨  -你好
- Hi. -‭ Hello.
宝贝  我回来了
Hey, babe.
-别用力关...  -别用力关...
- Oh, don't slam the... - Don't slam the...
真是又刺激又兴奋啊
That was exhilarating.
-你们去取裙子了吗  -是的
- You pick up your dresses? - Yep.
裁缝得把我的改紧一点  把佩妮的改松一点
The tailor had to take mine in and let Penny's out.
今天真是我这辈子最美好的一天
Best day of my life.
那你遇见我那天呢
What about the day you met me?
我维持原判
I stand by my statement.
谢谢你们送我们衣服
Well, thank you guys so much for the clothes
鞋子和机票
and the shoes, the plane tickets.
你们太慷慨了
You've been so generous.
我们看重的是能和所有朋友
Well, it's important that all of our friends
一起分享得奖时刻
get to share this moment with us.
未来很多年  你们可以告诉其他人
And then for years to come, you can tell others
你在第一排亲眼见证了历史
you had a front-row seat to history.
不过确切来说
Although, technically,
你们的座位在第二排
I think your seats are in the second row.
你想回公寓
Do you want to go back to the apartment
看我试穿裙子吗
and see me try on my dress?
我不是应该在诺贝尔颁奖典礼上第一次看到吗
Shouldn't I see it for the first time at the Nobel ceremony?
又不是结婚
It's not a wedding.
给我点时间让我想想
Okay. Well, give me a minute to think
我不想看到的其他原因
of another reason I don't want to see it.
这样吧  我试穿的时候你可以练习
How about this-- you can practice your acceptance speech
你的获奖感言
while I try on the dress.
太好了  你可以帮我缩减到90分钟
Ah, great. You can help me whittle it down to 90 minutes.
你的裙子要改松  艾米起疑心了吗
Was Amy suspicious when they had to let your dress out?
她太开心了  根本没有问
No. She was so happy, she didn't even question it.
总会有人发现的
Someone's gonna figure it out.
-何不现在就跟大家坦白呢  -不行  太早了
- Why don't we just tell people? - No, it's too early.
-我脑子还没完全转过来呢  -我转过来了
- I haven't even wrapped my head around it. - ‭I have.
-都要转个几圈了  -好吧
- My head is wrapped. - Yeah, well...
如果某人当时也"套"好转紧
if something else had been wrapped,
就不会搞成现在这样了
we wouldn't be in this situation.
不好意思啊  但我记得
Excuse me, but if I recall,
是你和谢尔顿出去喝酒
you're the one who went out drinking with Sheldon,
回家后向我主动进攻
then came home and attacked me.
进攻  我说的是"想来吗"
Attacked you? I said, "Do you wanna?"
对啊
Yeah.
我当时弱小又无助
I was helpless. ‭
那么...
So...
想来吗
do you wanna?
反正也不可能孕上加孕了
Well, I can't get more pregnant. ‭
走着瞧
We'll see about that.
翻译     最辛苦的莱纳赛 天才的谢尔独醉 别扭的艾米大菜 @少年影视派
校对     一切始于YY猫 一切终于赛太公
后期      灰灰是菇凉      时间轴    加森
总监     新浪微博@赛太公
生
活
大
爆
炸
第十二季  第二十四集[全剧终]
麦克  爸爸和妈妈
Now, Michael, Mommy and Daddy
要离开几天
are going away for a couple days,
如果你要说出人生中第一句话
so if you're gonna say your first words,
就现在说  否则就等我们回来再说
you got to do it now or wait till we get back.
某人刚刚尿在大宝宝的便壶里
Somebody just peed in the big girl potty.
我真为你骄傲
Oh, I'm so proud!
是她吧
It was her, right?
对
Yes.
你觉得把他们
You still feel good about leaving them
交给斯图尔特和德妮丝能行吗
with Stuart and Denise for a couple days?
应该吧  我只是希望不要错过麦克的第一句话
I guess. I just hope we don't miss Michael's first words.
或是斯图尔特的最后遗言
Or Stuart's last words.
你知道已经有好些年
You realize it's been years
我们没有独自出门了吧
since we've got away just the two of us.
我知道  我迫不及待
I know. I can't wait.
高级酒店房间  豪华大床
Fancy hotel room. The big bed.
对  我们要睡个昏天黑地
Yeah. We're gonna sleep our asses off.
你真觉得遛她可以帮助我认识女生吗
You really think walking her is gonna help me meet girls?
小桂子是吸女神器
Cinnamon is chick bait.
很好  因为我不是
Good. 'Cause I'm not.
记住
Just remember,
你是主人
you're in charge.
不要让她牵着你走
Don't let her pull you.
我这个吨位好像也不太可能吧
That seems like an unnecessary thing to say.
拜托  如果你有任何麻烦任何问题
And please, if you have any problems, any questions,
马上打给我  好吗
call me immediately, okay?
她是我的宝贝
She's my baby.
应该不会有问题  但以防万一
It shouldn't come up, but just in case:
我可以在哪里买到和她一模一样的狗
where could I buy a dog that looks exactly like her?
开玩笑的  如果她死了  我会直说
Kidding. If she dies, I'll just tell you.
准备好了吗
Ready?
稍等
Oh. Hang on.
开始
Go.
"国王和王后陛下  诺贝尔学院的各位院士
"Your majesties, members of the Nobel Academy--
我小时候在东德州长大
When I was a young boy growing up in East Texas
我一直知道我会登上这个舞台
I always knew I'd wind up on this stage,
所有说我没机会的人
And everybody who said I wouldn't looks
现在都像傻子
Pretty darn foolish right now.
我说的是你  高中科学老师休伯特·吉文斯"
I'm talking about you, high school science teacher Mr. Hubert Givens..."
谢尔顿
Sheldon, Sheldon.
你为什么说得这么快
Why are you talking so fast?
我想尽力把发言控制在90分钟内
I'm trying to get my speech down to 90 minutes.
没人能听明白你在说些什么
Nobody's gonna be able to understand a word you're saying.
你终于懂了我的人生
Welcome to my life.
我觉得你得做些删改
I think you need to do some editing,
也许去掉童年的部分吧
like maybe cut out all that stuff about your childhood.
开玩笑吗  在东德州的郊区长大
Are you kidding? Growing up in the backwoods of East Texas
令我成长为温暖可亲的人
is what makes me warm and relatable.
那么去掉点名那些
Well, what about all these pages
说你不会成功的人的名字的部分呢
calling out everyone who said you wouldn't succeed?
我跟他们说过有天他们会后悔的
I told them all they would rue the day.
如果这一天到来了  但他们却没有充满悔恨
How is it gonna make me look if the day finally comes,
那我面子往哪里挂
and they're not filled with rue?
谢尔顿  重点不是令人后悔
Sheldon, this isn't about ruing.
而是
This is about...
谦虚地接受无上的荣誉
humbly accepting a great honor.
艾米  我们赢得了诺贝尔物理学奖
Amy, we won the Nobel Prize in Physics.
谦虚是留给那些诺贝尔二流奖得主的
Humility is for people who win the goofy Nobels
比如说文学  经济  和平奖
like Literature, Economics and Peace.
拜托告诉我你的感言中没有这段话
Please tell me that's not in your speech.
我可以去掉  但这是我准备的唯一一个笑话
Oh. I can cut it, but it's the only joke I have.
放下百吉饼  在我们去机场前
All right, bagels down. Before we head to the airport,
我想再跟大家过几件事
I'd like to go over a few things.
我们从飞机上下来的那一刻起
From the moment we step off the plane,
你们每一位就成为我和艾米的大使
each and every one of you is an ambassador for Amy and myself.
早跟你说过世上没有白吃的午餐
I told you these tickets weren't free.
因此  你们的行为必须符合最高标准
As such, your behavior must reflect the highest standards.
拉杰  放下百吉饼
Uh, Raj. Bagel down.
如果我血糖低开始毒舌  那你就怪你自己
If my blood sugar drops and I get bitchy, it's on you.
艾米  不如你接着来
Amy, why don't you kick us off.
谢谢
Thank you.
"斯堪的纳维亚的恶劣气候
"The challenging climate of Scandinavia
在瑞典人的性格上烙下了印记
Has left its mark on the Swedish character.
那些严厉的现代维京人
These dour, latter-day Vikings
对待陌生人会比较慢热
Are slow to warm up to strangers,
但如果你遵照以下简单几步
But if you follow a few easy steps,
瑞典人也可以成为你的终生朋友"
a Swede can be your friend for life."
第一
"Number one,
"在瑞典 守时是十分重要的
"In Sweden, punctuality is taken very seriously.
换句话说就是 芬兰人那种拖拉懒散的态度
"In other words, the loosey-goosey attitude in Helsinki
在斯德哥尔摩是行不通的"
will not fly in Stockholm."
"第二  在所有
"Two, at the beginning
商业社交场合的开始与结束时间
"And end of all business and social meetings,
要与在场的每一个人握手
"Shake hands with everyone present--
包括男人  女人和孩子"
men, women and children."
并且鼓励大家乘坐飞机时
Yes, you're all encouraged to pair off and practice this
等待安全带指示灯熄灭后 两人一组排练起来
once we're in the air and the seat belt sign is off.
请说  佩妮
Yes, Penny? ‭Oh.
我们非去不可吗
Do we have to go?
是的  提醒你  佩妮  商务舱的酒免费
Yes. And a reminder, Penny, there's free alcohol
请你不要狂饮
in business class-- don't abuse it.
放心  我不会喝的
Relax. I'm not gonna drink.
-为什么  你怀孕了吗  -什么  没有
- Why? You pregnant?  - Wha...? No.
没有  我只是
No, I just, you know,
不喜欢坐飞机喝酒
I don't like to drink when I fly.
得了吧  我看过你在洗澡时喝酒
Please. I've seen you drink in the shower.
你们两个人一起洗过澡吗
You guys have showered together?
有时候你真是
Sometimes you're just...
恶
ech.
你没否认哦
That wasn't a no.
我们现在该出发了  要在登机前六小时
All right, well, we should head out now if we're gonna get
准时到达机场
to the airport six hours before boarding.
等一下  各位  我们刚刚学的
Excuse me. Hello? What did we
在商务见面结束后该怎么做来着
just learn about the end of business meetings?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
好  非常好  随便吧
Yeah, great. Whatever.
继续
Go on.
你先走  走
You first. Go.
等等
Wait.
救命
Help me! ‭Oh.
-救命  -等等  过来
- Help me! - Oh, wait. Come here.
-我们可以的  -进来  进来
- We got this. - Yeah, get in, get in, get in.
等一下  我有个主意
Hang on. I've-I've got an idea.
做得好  你证明了自己
Well done. You know, you're proving to be
是我的随从中不可或缺的一份子
an invaluable part of my entourage.
好耶
Cool.
怎么了
Yeah?
-你怎么样  -挺好的  干嘛
- How you doing? - Fine. Why?
这是我们第一次离孩子这么远
Well, this is the furthest we've ever been away from the kids.
就是看看你怎么样
I was just checking to see if you're okay.
在看第二部《侠探杰克》感觉好极了
I'm on my second Jack Reacher. I'm doing great.
很好  我也是
Good. Me, too.
我刚刚看着地图
I was just looking at the map.
忍不住想到  我们在这儿
Couldn't help thinking: we're here
孩子们在那  如果发生了什么事
and they're there, and if anything happened,
我们就得先飞到这里  才能飞回去那里
we'd have to go here to get all the way back there.
你干嘛要让我也紧张起来
Why are you trying to freak me out?
这是我们的假期
This is our vacation.
觉得我们得一起感受些什么
I thought we should do things together.
霍华德  孩子们很好
Howard, the kids are okay.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
我就是知道  妈妈全都知道
I just know. A mother knows.
怎么  原力与你同在了
So what, now the Force is with you?
试一试
Let's see.
这是你绝对不想惹的女人[心灵控制]
This is not the woman you want to annoy.
-霍华德  霍华德  -干嘛
- Howard. Howard. ‭- What?
你看看坐我旁边的那个女人
You see the woman sitting next to me?
她怎么了
What about her?
是不是她
Is this her?
《吸血鬼猎人巴菲》吗
Buffy the Vampire Slayer?
冷静
Shh! Be cool.
不  不是她
No, that's not her. ‭
好  现在你再看
Okay. How about now?
两个小时里  她已经去厕所
That's the fourth time she's been to the bathroom
整整4次了
in the last two hours.
所以呢
So?
她吃的早餐没有问题  我是确认过的
Her breakfast was binding. I made sure of that.
-所以呢  -所以很明显
- So? - ‭So she clearly has
她有某种肠胃疾病
some sort of stomach distress.
如果是病毒性的  我们都有危险
If it's viral, we're all susceptible.
她可能只是晕机了
She's probably just airsick.
对  可如果不是呢
Yeah, but what if she's not?
万一我们被她传染了
What if we get what she has?
万一瑞典国王被我们传染了呢
What if we infect the King of Sweden?
战争就是这么开始的
That's how wars start.
确定了  这就是《极度恐慌》的剧情  她是那只猴
All right, that's it, this is Outbreak and she's the monkey.
等等  不要
Wait. Stop.
理智点
Be reasonable.
莱纳德
Leonard...
我们需要处理一下你的妻子
we need to do something about your wife.
-怎么了  -她很明显病了
- What's the matter?-  She is clearly sick,
我们所有人都会被她拖累的
and she's gonna take us all down with her.
她没病  谢尔顿
She's not sick, Sheldon.
她有病  而且我会被传染
She is, and I'm gonna catch it,
我这辈子最重要的一天就要被毁掉了
and it's gonna ruin the greatest day of my life.
我保证  你肯定不会染上她的症状
I promise you're not going to get what she has.
怎么了
What's going on?
不洁净  不洁净
Unclean! Unclean!
什么
What?
他觉得你生病了
He thinks you're sick.
我们要不要告诉他
Should we tell him?
如果我们不告诉他
Well, if we don't, he might try
他会吵着要跳机的
and jump out of the plane. ‭
对  但并没有回答我的问题
Yeah. Doesn't answer my question.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
我怀孕了  谢尔顿
I'm pregnant, Sheldon.
你说得对  我肯定不会染上她这症状
You're right, I can't catch that.
好消息  艾米
Good news, Amy.
她只是怀孕了
She's just pregnant.
你在开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
你刚刚得知一个关怀爱护了你十二年的女人
You just found out that a woman who has loved and cared for you
她怀孕了  而你却只说
for 12 years is pregnant, and all you can say is
她不会让你得病  你放心了
you're relieved that she's not gonna get you sick?
不用给我总结
There's no need for a recap.
我刚刚在场
I was there.
-你怎么没告诉我  -我没告诉任何人
- Why didn't you tell me? - I didn't tell anybody.
我不是随便任何人  我是你最好的朋友
I'm not anybody. I'm your best friend.
-怎么了  -她怀孕了
- What's going on? ‭- She's pregnant.
太好了
That's fantastic!
你怎么之前没告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
她也没告诉我
She didn't tell me, either.
但我是她最好的朋友啊
But I'm her best friend.
我们之后再来谈这个
We'll get into that later.
你不是说你永远不会生孩子吗
What happened to "I'm never gonna have kids"?
那是个意外  我那天跟谢尔顿一起出去喝酒了
It was an accident. I went out drinking with Sheldon.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
我们是"共夫姐妹"吗
We're sister wives?
不是  我喝完回家跟莱纳德睡了
No. Then I went home and slept with Leonard.
-但脑海里幻想的是...  -莱纳德
- While fantasizing about... - Leonard.
也意淫了下性感男星艾德里斯·艾巴
And a little Idris Elba.
-我是说  他实在...  -没错
- I mean, ah... ‭- Oh, yeah.
你希望我说什么
What would you like me to say?
祝贺一下我们怎么样
How about congratulating us?
祝贺你们合适吗
Are congratulations even in order?
我以为佩妮根本不想生孩子
I didn't think Penny wanted children.
她之前是不想  现在想了
Well, she didn't, now she does.
再告诉你一下
And just so you know,
我们本来并不打算说出来的
we weren't gonna tell anybody
不想在你的大日子抢你的风头
so we wouldn't upstage your big day.
拜托  这风头你们想抢也抢不了
Oh, please, you couldn't upstage us.
我们可是赢了诺贝尔奖啊
We won a Nobel Prize.
而任何一个白痴都能生孩子
Any idiot can have a baby.
怎么了
Hey. What's going on?
活生生的例子来了
Case in point.
你就是个自私的混蛋
You are a selfish jerk.
你和你的诺贝尔奖都去死吧
To hell with you and your Nobel Prize.
我在她的包里翻到了她的登机牌
I found her boarding pass in her purse.
就是她了  实锤
It's totally her.
斯图尔特  就了解下情况
Hi, Stuart, just checking in.
看是否一切都好
Seeing if everything's okay.
当然了  我们玩得很开心
Oh, yeah, we're having fun.
我  哈雷和德妮丝玩了一整天的捉迷藏
Me, Halley and Denise played hide-and-seek all day.
-真不错  -是啊
- Oh, that's nice. - Yeah.
我一下子就找到德妮丝了
I found Denise right away.
哈雷藏在哪儿了
Where was Halley hiding?
重要的是  她现在不在那里了
Uh, the important thing is she's not there now.
好吧  所以大家都开心又健康吗
Okay, so, everyone's happy and healthy?
那得看情况了
Well, that depends.
这话什么意思
What's that mean?
你们离开时  哈雷有多少颗牙
Uh, how many teeth did Halley have when you left?
满嘴的牙
All of them.
好吧  那正是我害怕的情况
Oh, yeah, that's-that's what I was afraid of.
发生什么事了
What happened?
好吧  我说了
Um, well, all right.
麦克昨晚发烧了
Um, Michael had a little fever last night.
麦克发烧了吗
Michael had a fever?
你们到底想不想听哈雷的情况了
Do you want to hear about Halley or not?
发生什么事了  斯图尔特
What happened, Stuart?
他有点发烧  不用担心
He was running a little fever, nothing to worry about.
哈雷这个贴心小宝贝
And Halley, bless her heart,
想把他的安慰熊送去给他
wanted to bring him his boo-boo bear,
所以她翻过防护栏
so she climbed over the safety rail
从楼梯上滚了下来
and took a little tumble down the stairs.
她从楼梯上摔了下来
She fell down the stairs?!
她是从楼梯上滚下去的
She rolled down the stairs,
全程一直在笑
laughing the whole time.
总之  等她滚到底部的时候
Anyway, when she got to the bottom,
就少了颗牙
there was a tooth missing.
斯图尔特
Oh, Stuart!
她没事
She's fine!
她还觉得这很好玩呢
She thought it was funny.
你有没有保存下来给牙仙
Did you at least save it for the tooth fairy?
没有  我们找不到
No, we couldn't find it.
我们大概知道在哪里
We have a theory about where it is,
但要等到6到8小时后才能确认
but it'll take six to eight hours to confirm.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
你们家的意面过滤盆放在哪儿了
where do you keep the spaghetti strainer?
拜托  你不会真指望他的反应
Come on, you didn't seriously expect him to react
跟正常人一样吧
like a normal human being.
那倒没有  但经过这么多年
No, but still, a-after all these years,
我忍受了他那么多臭毛病
after all the crap I've put up with,
我还以为哪怕就这么一次
you'd think just this once
他可以做到在乎别人的感受
he'd care about someone else's feelings.
-天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God! - ‭What?
盐腌鲱鱼  真没想到竟然这么好吃
Pickled herring. Who knew how good it was!
真的吗
Really?
听着很恶心  看着很恶心  闻着很恶心
Sounds gross. Looks gross. Smells gross.
尝着太美味
It's delicious!
肯定是我点的盐腌鳕鱼来了
Ooh, that might be my salted cod!
什么事
What?
谢尔顿有话对你们说
Sheldon has something he'd like to say.
我很抱歉我之前的反应很不恰当
I'm sorry I didn't react appropriately.
你和佩妮即将迎来新生命
You and Penny are bringing new life into the world.
恭喜了  我也迫不及待想见到它
Congratulations. I can't wait to meet it.
-"它"  -那是个中性的代词
- "It"? ‭- That's a gender-neutral pronoun.
如果你觉得被冒犯  去找英语这门语言撕逼吧
If you're offended, take it up with the English language.
太好了  你们在这里  听我说
Oh, good, you're here. Listen,
我们想着要不要坐飞机回洛杉矶
we're thinking maybe we should go back to L.A.
-为什么  -我们离孩子这么远实在不放心
- Why? ‭- We just can't be this far away from the kids.
妮妮快崩溃了
Bernie's having a meltdown,
老实说  我也一样
and, frankly, so am I.
振作一下啊  这可是我的大日子
Yeah, well, pull it together. This is a big day for me.
好吧  我之前还不确定该怎么做
Yeah, I wasn't sure what to do.
现在我确定了  我们要回家
Now I am. We're going home.
我们跟你们一起
We'll join you. ‭
等等  我有发言权吗
Oh, wait. Do I get a vote in this?
飞机上也有盐腌鲱鱼
They'll have pickled herring on the plane.
再见
Bye-bye.
我也不想这么说
Well, I hate to say it,
但我觉得大家都太自私了
but I think everyone is being incredibly selfish.
这方面你最有发言权了
Well, you would be the authority on the subject.
你这话什么意思
What does that mean?
谢尔顿  能赢得诺贝尔奖  没人比我更开心
Sheldon, no one is happier than I am to win the Nobel.
但这远没有我们的朋友重要
But it's not more important than our friends.
他们都要抛下我们了  还算什么朋友
How can you call them friends when they're abandoning us?
他们要抛下我们
They're abandoning us
是因为你伤了他们的心
because you broke their hearts.
-我不是有意的  -我知道
- I didn't mean to. - ‭I know!
你从来都不是故意的
You never mean to.
这也是大家容忍你的唯一原因
That's the only reason people tolerate you!
连你也这样吗
Does that include you?
有时候  是的
Sometimes, yeah.
好了  鱼的部分吐完了
Okay, that's it for the fish.
接下来很快回到肉丸单元
We'll be back with the meatballs
在那之前请先听听我们赞助商的发言
after a short word from our sponsor.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
莱纳德  我不能回去
Leonard, I can't go home.
-我得留在这陪艾米  -我知道
- I have to be there for Amy. - ‭Yeah.
我刚才也在想这件事
I was thinking that, too.
虽然我很生谢尔顿的气
As angry as I am at Sheldon,
但我还是想看着他赢得那块奖牌
I still want to see him win that medal.
真的好奇怪啊
It's so strange.
无论那家伙有多不懂事多自私
No matter how thoughtless and selfish he is,
我还是爱他
I still love him.
如果换个角度想
If you think about it,
他也算是我们多年的练习版孩子了
he has kind of been our practice kid.
就像大家做松饼的时候
Like when you make pancakes
第一张饼总是比较歪七扭八
and the first one comes out a little wonky.
大学更愿意称其为"怪杰"
The university prefers "quirky."
你好
Hello.
怎么样  是霍华德
Hey. It's Howard.
我们也是
Oh, us, too.
-等等  怎么了  -他们也想留下
- Wait, what? - They're gonna stay.
孩子们没事了  妮妮的父母接手了
The kids are fine. Bernie's parents took over.
真的吗
Really?
小可怜
Oh, poor little guy.
麦克还好吧
Is Michael okay?
没事  是斯图尔特有事
Yeah, it's Stuart.
妮妮的爸爸给他个拥抱  他断了根肋骨
Bernie's dad gave him a hug, cracked a rib.
好  那我们楼下大厅碰头
Yeah. Okay, we'll meet you in the lobby.
你大概需要多久能准备好
How long is it gonna take you to get ready?
给我个5到10分钟就行了
Oh, I just need, like, five or ten minutes.
-真的假的  -当然假的  你白痴啊
- Really? - No. What is wrong with you?!
物理学奖的获得者是
And in the field of physics,
艾米·菲拉·福勒博士
Dr. Amy Farrah Fowler
与谢尔顿·库珀博士
and Dr. Sheldon Cooper
他们发现了超不对称性
for their discovery of super-asymmetry.
先说清楚  这不是约会
Just to be clear, this isn't a date.
我知道啊
Yeah, I know.
那你干嘛牵我的手
Then why are you holding my hand?
谢谢您  国王陛下
Thank you, your majesties.
谢谢诺贝尔奖委员会
Thank you to the Nobel Committee.
我们深感荣幸
We are deeply honored.
我想借由这个机会
I would just like to take this moment
向全天下梦想投身
to say to all the young girls out there
科学界的小女孩说
who dream about science as a profession:
勇敢追梦吧
go for it.
这是世界上最棒的工作
It is the greatest job in the world.
如果有人说你们不行  别听他的
And if anybody tells you you can't, don't listen.
现在呢
And now,
说到不听人说话
speaking of not listening,
有请我丈夫  谢尔顿·库珀博士
my husband, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
怎么  你说完了吗  说得真棒
What? Did you finish? Great job.
谢谢你  福勒博士
Thank you, Dr. Fowler.
我准备了一段
I have a very long
又臭又长还有点以自我中心的演讲稿
and somewhat self-centered speech here.
但我决定不照念了
But I'd like to set it aside.
-太好了  -干得好
- Yeah! - Way to go!
因为这份荣誉并不只属于我一个人
Because this honor doesn't just belong to me.
我此刻能有幸站在这里
I wouldn't be up here if it weren't
得感谢我生命中一些十分重要的人
for some very important people in my life.
首先是我的母亲  父亲  姥姥
Beginning with my mother, father, meemaw,
哥哥与姐姐
brother and sister.
然后还有我另一个家庭
And my other family,
我很高兴他们今天也在场
who I'm so happy to have here with us.
那是《吸血鬼猎人巴菲》吗
Is that Buffy the Vampire Slayer?
我之前对我的成就有误解
I was under a misapprehension
觉得这一切都是我自己的功劳
that my accomplishments were mine alone.
但事实完全不是如此
Nothing could be further from the truth.
一直以来  我受到的鼓励支持
I have been encouraged, sustained,
激励与容忍
inspired and tolerated
不仅来自我的妻子
not only by my wife,
还来自世界上最好的一群朋友
but by the greatest group of friends anyone ever had.
现在我想请他们起立
I'd like to ask them to stand.
拉杰什·库萨帕里博士
Dr. Rajesh Koothrappali.
伯纳黛特·罗斯滕科斯基·沃罗威茨博士
Dr. Bernadette Rostenkowski Wolowitz.
宇航员霍华德·沃罗威茨
Astronaut Howard Wolowitz.
以及我世上最好的两个挚友
And my two dearest friends in the world,
佩妮·霍夫斯塔德
Penny Hofstadter...
以及莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德博士
...and Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
莱纳德与佩妮初次相遇时我在场
I was there the moment Leonard and Penny met.
他对我说"他们的孩子一定会又聪明又好看"
He said to me that their babies would be smart and beautiful.
而现在他们即将迎来新生命
And now that they're expecting,
我毫不怀疑这孩子会像他说的那样
I have no doubt that that will be the case.
谢谢祝福  谢尔顿
Thanks, Sheldon.
我还没告诉我爸妈  但谢了
I-I haven't told my parents yet, but thanks.
对不起啦
Oh. I'm sorry.
别外传最后说的这件事
Don't tell anyone that last thing.
这是个秘密
That's a secret.
霍华德  伯纳黛特
Howard, Bernadette,
拉杰  佩妮  莱纳德
Raj, Penny, Leonard,
抱歉我一直不是个称职的朋友
I apologize if I haven't been the friend you deserve.
但我希望你们知道
But I want you to know
我用我的方式  爱着你们所有人
in my way, I love you all.
我也爱你
And I love you.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
♪ 我们的宇宙曾经超热又超密 ♪
♪ Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ 直到大约140亿年前的某一天 ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years ago ♪
♪ 宇宙膨胀开始了  等等 ♪
♪ Expansion started... Wait ♪
♪ 地球开始冷却 ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ 自养生物开始发育  尼安德塔人发明工具 ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ 我们建了长城  我们建了金字塔 ♪
♪ We built a Wall, we built the pyramids ♪
♪ 数学  科学  历史 ♪
♪ Math, Science, History ♪
♪ 解开了谜团 ♪
♪ Unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ 一切都始于大爆炸 ♪
♪ That all started with a big bang. ♪